<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>UMKL News</title>
		<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/</link>
		<description>The latest news from the UMKL</description>
		<language>en-gb</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:47:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<image>
			<title>UMKL News</title>
			<url>assets/media/brand/favicon.png</url>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/</link>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>Season 2 Round 1 Fixtures Revealed!</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-10-01/season-2-round-1-fixtures-revealed/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/season2fixtures.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first round of Season 2 fixtures have been revealed, and we are kicking things off in style. In the coming weeks we will see 6 matches fought between 12 universities across the UK, and all of these will be live on the UMKL YouTube channel for you to enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eISfD64peMI"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or watch the video below to see watch matches will take place in round 1!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/eISfD64peMI?si=KuW-4UfnSO1KWxbh"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-10-01/season-2-round-1-fixtures-revealed/round2fixtures.avif"/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Teams will compete in these matches in October.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=York"&gt;York&lt;/a&gt; VS &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=BIMM"&gt;BIMM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                    Our Season 1 title holders York are drawn against the oldest of newcomer teams BIMM. These teams last played 
                    a test match together in &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/?date=2025-06-13"&gt;June&lt;/a&gt;, which fell in York's favour by a score of 
                    &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/tools/6v6scorecalculator/?m=JoewTg1gBAagylAQgSQLKqgCgCoFMDOALlKgIaEDGAFgJRA&amp;amp;p=EwGgzCCsIOwgHCAjEgUKAbLBICczhUkRQAWKHFVCc6LOJABiJPAocONBot1WjiJ8TAi0w5haLtmGNR3CvWTM62RClHEeQ5UA&amp;amp;t=MwEQygBA0g9jAOBDCBhAlgFwJ4CgDqaANgCYR5zEDOOA4igHIQCaMlAFmqmgE4DGArphz00AOwBWyABJpiAU0QB3RLgCCotAFtEhVN1aUxAc3xpOIRGkpYufQRlOcAsnFEA3NHMUQZRtstwAITQjCEDCfjlhADYAFggAJRgsHUTEXi8VHHAyHUEjTgAFMQAjHUIcUEgQKAgAKX5RI0Iogk4UGF4YUX4MCCdyoA&amp;amp;n=JoewTg1gUAQgkgWQUA"&gt;516 - 468&lt;/a&gt;. 
                    Will York carry their momentum forward, or will BIMM upset the champions?
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Staffs"&gt;Staffs&lt;/a&gt; VS &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Glasgow"&gt;Glasgow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                    The runners up from Season 1 Staffs will be playing Glasgow in a chaotic first round tie. These teams 
                    have met once before, back in &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/?date=2025-04-27"&gt;April&lt;/a&gt; with a victory in favour of Staffs. Can Glasgow bite back, or will 
                    Staffs continue their good run of form?
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Edinburgh"&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/a&gt; VS &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Brighton"&gt;Brighton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                    The newest addition to the UMKL roster, Brighton, will face Season 1 veterans Edinburgh 
                    in their debut outing. With Edinburgh last playing back in February, Brighton could 
                    certainly test the waters and snatch a hard fought result. A fun watch is definitely in 
                    store with this fixture, but which team can take home the win?
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Keele"&gt;Keele&lt;/a&gt; VS &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Uosheff"&gt;Uosheff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                    Uosheff might fancy their chances against Keele, who rounded off the table in their last outing. Keele last 
                    played a match in April, with a loss to their local rivals in Staffs, while Uosheff are yet to play a 
                    competitive fixture. Who will come out on top in this clash of underdogs?
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Birmingham"&gt;Birmingham&lt;/a&gt; VS &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Liverpool"&gt;Liverpool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                    Our first clash of the newcomers sees Liverpool play Birmingham in a tantalising competitive debut. 
                    Birmingham have chalked up impressive results in test matches recently, against &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/?date=2025-08-05"&gt;Warwick&lt;/a&gt; 
                    and &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/?date=2025-08-06"&gt;Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;, 
                    but can Liverpool catch them by surprise in their first ever match?
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Warwick"&gt;Warwick&lt;/a&gt; VS &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/teams/details/?team=Cambridge"&gt;Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                    A blockbuster tie sees Cambridge, with an upset win against York in their 
                    &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/?date=2025-08-29"&gt;last match&lt;/a&gt;, 
                    against a red hot Warwick side in an action packed match, where the winner takes all. 
                    Which of these new teams will make their mark on an incredible first round in the new 
                    season?
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Best of luck to all our teams, and may the best team win!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Structure for Season 2</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-09-29/the-structure-for-season-2/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/season2structure.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The upcoming season of UMKL will be using a Swiss Style system to determine the winner, but what exactly is that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-09-29/the-structure-for-season-2/season2structureupdated.avif"/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Season 2 is scheduled to start in October 2025.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                A Swiss System Tournament, most commonly used in chess, draws opponents against each other based on their 
                current standings and match records, resulting in closer matches and near accurate skill based matchmaking. 
                This simply means that teams who win will play teams who win, and teams who lose will play teams who lose; 
                there is no 'elimination' and everybody gets to keep on playing!
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                This system allows us to reduce the number of matchdays required for each team, which helps 
                when most players are also full time students, and with the huge influx in teams this season 
                it's just not feasible nor efficient to play almost 70 matches in the space of a few months.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a Swiss System we reduce that number down to 24 matches, which will be closer fought and 
                more entertaining for both players and the audience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Season 2 starting in October we hope that everyone enjoys the upcoming matches, and we look forward to seeing our teams back in action very soon!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;
                    This article is an explation of an announcement made on the UMKL Discord server, 
                    you can join the server here.
                &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cheep Cheep Updates</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-07-17/cheep-cheep-updates/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/newcommands.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi all! Here are a few updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                It's been a few months since the announcement of 
                &lt;mention&gt;@Cheep Cheep&lt;/mention&gt; app, 
                since then a lot of new commands and features have been added.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Work is being done constantly to improve the stability of our 
                systems we use for UMKL, so we hope everyone is happy with the 
                continued development!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important change from the 
                previous message is that the &lt;code&gt;/register&lt;/code&gt; has been removed, as 
                it is no longer required to use &lt;code&gt;/join&lt;/code&gt; when you're joining a 
                team. A full changelog will be listed at the end of this page.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                A few test matches have occurred recently and they've gone smoothly, 
                so more test matches will follow! 
                So be sure to check the &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/"&gt;matches&lt;/a&gt; page
                for upcoming matches!
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below are some newly added commands that can be used in the server!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-07-17/cheep-cheep-updates/newcommands.avif"/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Changelog for the 17/07/2025 update&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/register&lt;/code&gt; removed, it is no longer required to use &lt;code&gt;/join&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New command - &lt;code&gt;/leaderboards&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatted &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;DD/MM/YYYY&lt;/code&gt; in embeds (only for outputted text, not for command inputs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the match versus image on the sign-up embed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the date in the sign-up embed to a timestamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New command - &lt;code&gt;/change-team-colour&lt;/code&gt; (board only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal changes to SQL/DB threading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal changes to the API used on &lt;code&gt;umkl.co.uk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweaked graphics to add shadowing beneath text to improve contrast and readability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New command - &lt;code&gt;/generate-stream-overlay&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &lt;code&gt;/team-profile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New commands (used for streaming overlay):
                        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/add-results-to-liveresults&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/edit-results-in-liveresults&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/reset-liveresults&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New command - &lt;code&gt;/submit-room-code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New command - &lt;code&gt;/report-disconnection&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some easter eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;
                    This article is a summary of an announcement made on the UMKL Discord server, 
                    you can join the server here.
                &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Upcoming summer test matches!</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-06-13/upcoming-summer-test-matches/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/summertestmatches.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;More test matches between teams are being planned throughout the weeks as exams finish and summer approaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please check the &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/"&gt;matches&lt;/a&gt; page to see confirmed and upcoming matches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now is also a good time for board members to liaise with other universities and plan test matches with each other, especially if your team hasn't had a Test Match yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-06-13/upcoming-summer-test-matches/versus.avif"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;A match graphic, as seen in the events tab on the Discord server.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                These continued test matches further test the Cheep Cheep application and YouTube streaming. Members of the relevant 
                teams can sign up to compete in this match using the button in the team's announcement channel.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                These matches will be streamed on the UMKL YouTube channel. 
                You can watch upcoming livestreams &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@universitymariokartleague/streams"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Test matches are being conducted!</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-22/umkl-test-matches-are-being-conducted/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/testmatches.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test matches are planned in the upcoming week, more will follow in the upcoming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please check the &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/matches/"&gt;matches&lt;/a&gt; page to see confirmed and upcoming matches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-22/umkl-test-matches-are-being-conducted/versus.avif"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;A match graphic, as seen in the events tab on the Discord server.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                The upcoming test matches will serve as a test of the Cheep Cheep app and YouTube streaming. Members of the relevant 
                teams can sign up to compete in this match using the button in the team's announcement channel.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                These matches will be streamed from both team's perspectives on the UMKL YouTube channel. 
                You can visit it &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@universitymariokartleague"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Information for universities wanting to join</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-19/uni-joining-info/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/mariokartbanner.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Intro&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Joining the University Mario Kart League is a commitment to the future of Mario Kart e-sports in the United Kingdom, 
                and we would love to have your university represented in the league. 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                The UMKL presents an exciting opportunity for students across the country to make connections 
                and have fun alongside their studies, while also providing a look into the growing competitive scene of Mario Kart.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Being a part of the University Mario Kart League is a responsibility. 
                University teams are expected to maintain a level of activity throughout the season, 
                as with many teams comes a greater weight on scheduling. 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Teams are also expected to act respectfully 
                and dignified to both their opponents and their peers, and we reserve the right to pull a team from the 
                league if they are acting in problematic manner.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-19/uni-joining-info/mariokartbanner.avif"/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Season 2 is scheduled to start in October 2025.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Creating a New Team&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                If you are interested in creating a new team in the UMKL to represent your university, please check whether there
                are enough players at your university who are interested in participating. 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                A team must have a minimum of six players
                available to play in every match, so make sure there are more than enough players to fill this requirement.
                Members of your university do not need to play in matches to be part of your team.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                University teams should not be tied to a specific society in a university. Although specific societies in
                the university may be Mario Kart or e-sports/gaming focused, anybody in the univeristy should be free 
                to join the team regardless of their affiliation with these specific societies.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Important&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                All efforts must be made within your university's team to include everyone, such as discussing 
                match line-ups in the UMKL server (not in a separate society's server 
                that some members may not have access to, as an example) and keeping teamwide practise to within 
                the UMKL server.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This is important to keep the UMKL free and open for everyone.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                Promotion of the UMKL via society channels is allowed, but a distinction must be made
                about how you do not need to be part of that society to be part of the UMKL team.
                Please read the &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/rules/brand/"&gt;Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; page for more details about how you can
                use UMKL intellectual property and content. 
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Please note that current students, alumni, university faculty and prospective students (holding an offer)
                are welcome to join your team, but students outside of your university may not be allowed.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                Please visit the &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/rules/team/"&gt;Team Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; page
                for rules associated with a new team's credentials
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Teams should thoroughly brief themselves on the &lt;a href="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/rules/match/"&gt;match rules&lt;/a&gt; and relay this information to 
                their players before forming a team. The majority of our matches are livestreamed and recorded 
                for entertainment and promotion, and teams should also make their players aware of this. Players should
                be briefed on this fact and be told about the consequences of misconduct should it occur on our live matches.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Once teams have completed the above requirements, they should contact the board with 
                their request to join and we will review it. This is best done on the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/jz3hKEmDss"&gt;UMKL Discord server&lt;/a&gt;.
                If accepted, your team will be inducted into the following season of the league. A season will 
                typically begin in October, and end in April, with matches taking a break during the winter holidays.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                If accepted, the board will ask your team to nominate two individuals to join 
                the board. These members will then be able to use the &lt;code&gt;/create-team&lt;/code&gt; command.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                We hope that everything here is clear, and we look forward to seeing your team 
                joining the UMKL and competing in the next season. For any questions, queries or inquiries 
                contact any of the board members and we would be more than happy to help!
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                You can join our Discord server &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/jz3hKEmDss"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
                and find our YouTube channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@universitymariokartleague"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Join the UMKL Discord server!</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-19/umkl-discord/</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/discordinspire.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                The University Mario Kart League 
                &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/jz3hKEmDss"&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; is the beating heart of our operations.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                From match organisation, to game results and general UMKL activity, the Discord server is the fastest way to keep up to date with the UMKL.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                The server is also a thriving hub for all UMKL news, and is a great way to connect with other players and make friends across the UK. 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/brand/cheep_cheep_banner_cropped.avif"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;With the Cheep Cheep app, users can fetch player and match data in the server.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Featured in our Discord server is our bespoke app - Cheep Cheep, ready to provide 
                data about players in the UMKL, stats about teams. It can also manage a team's current roster before each match, 
                and generate sleek custom images after every match, showing a team and player's score, along with the standings
                for a current season.
                &lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;
                    The Cheep Cheep app was developed by Adeola Adeniji, zy and Tushar Sundarka,
                    please visit the credits for all UMKL credits.
                &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's also loaded with a bunch of tools helping board members manage matches and teams. This all ensures smooth running of the league.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                The server is also the quickest way to contact the UMKL board, 
                who are happy to answer any of your questions and queries. 
                This is helpful for upcoming teams and universities who 
                might be interested in taking part in future seasons.
                &lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;
                    Please visit Information for universities wanting to join
                    for more information on this topic.
                &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Whether you're a player, a committee member or a fan, 
                come join our Discord server and be a part of our lovely community! 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                You can join our Discord server &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/jz3hKEmDss"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Welcome to the UMKL!</title>
			<link>https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-19/umkl-intro</link>
			<media:content url="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/news/umklbanner.avif" type="image/avif" medium="image"> </media:content>
			<description>&lt;![CDATA[ &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the University Mario Kart League!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've reached this page, you probably have an idea of what we do, but we'll explain more below!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                We're an independent gaming league made up of university teams across the country,
                which compete in 6v6 Mario Kart 8 Deluxe matches.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                This project started last year, where we had four university teams in play, 
                but this has quickly expanded to universities across the country! Currently 
                we're still growing, with 6v6 test matches and friendlies being played until our 
                next season starts next academic year.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/assets/media/brand/promo/UMKL_Season_2_Teaser.avif"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Season 2 is scheduled to start in October 2025.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're one season down, with our reigning champions York topping the charts for Season 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://umkl.co.uk/pages/news/2025-04-19/umkl-intro/teamstandings.avif"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Some team logos were incomplete during Season 1.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                Currently, whilst we're working on our website and the next season's roster, we are currently 
                having on-going test matches between our teams and practice rooms.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                The UMKL discord is growing daily, with more and more interest being shown in our matches and livestreams,
                as we carve out our own little niche in gaming culture.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
                We are run by students, for students, and remain dedicated 
                to forging connections between universities. Our 6v6 comp format gives uni groups 
                ample opportunity to communicate with each other, 
                improve their Mario Kart 8 Deluxe skills, and grow as a team together. 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
                With 12 players and 12 races per match, get ready to 
                practice your green shell snipes, bomb throws,
                and to communicate effectively as a team to speed towards victory!
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                You can join our Discord server &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/jz3hKEmDss"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
                Our YouTube channel, where we livestream matches, can be visited &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@universitymariokartleague"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
                Please visit the credits to see everyone who worked on the University Mario Kart League.
            &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt; ]]&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
